PERSONAL INFORMATION

Luca Arrigo



- 150 COUNTRY CLUB DR, 02038 Franklin MA (United States)
- **+**1(617)459-9821
- Iuca@arrigo.io
- https://github.com/m0rph84

Skype luky_luke84 | Google Hangouts morph84@gmail.com

Sex Male | Date of birth 03/10/1984 | Nationality Italian

PREFERRED JOB

- ICT System Administrator
- Software Developer

GOALS

After a career of more than 10 years that led me to the Sysadmin specialization and to work in the IT world both in Italy and United States, I now feel the need for change and for new professional challenges.

I would like to go back to Europe and continue to pursue my carrier as a System engineer or specialize in what first fueled my passion for computer science, programming. This would allow me to put myself on the line and follow my passion for software development.

In short, I'm looking for a company that gives me the chance to get back in the game and that believe in my abilities, willingness to learn and work hard to achieve my new goals.

WORK EXPERIENCE

01/04/2015-Present

ICT Senior System Administrator

Uno Communications Inc., Boston (United States)

- Hardware/software Installation, configuration and maintenance of MVTS II and Mediacore VoIP soft-switch servers.
- 5-year experience with VoIP engineering, hands-on with VoIP and telecom equipment, standards and technologies.
- Installation, configuration and maintenance of servers and virtual servers based on Linux/Windows Server 2012/2016 operating systems and VMware/Hyper-V virtualization systems
- Servers and networks monitoring and troubleshooting with tools like PRTG and remote or local intervention (Datacenter).



Curriculum vitae Luca Arrigo

- Creation of simple **Python's scripts** to automate repetitive tasks.
- Coordination and management of the technical support team.
- Second-level Help desk support to our wholesale clients.

Business or sector Information and communication

10/01/2009-31/03/2015

ICT system administrator

Uno Communications SPA, Imperia (Italy)

- MVTS II VoIP soft-switch management.
- SOHO routers configuration.
- Creation of internal technical documentation.
- Providing support for end customers and companies about HPDSL and ADSL Internet services.
- Monitoring and troubleshooting problems on the Liguria's HPDSL network.
- Resolution of VolP quality problematic.
- Maintenance on **Servers** for our local **data center**.
- Development support of the company's Intranet based on HTML+CSS+ASP.NET

Business or sector Information and communication

01/01/2007-30/09/2009

ICT system administrator

12 s.r.l. (British Telecom Group company), Genova (Italy)

- Installation, configuration and maintenance of Linux/Windows servers and virtual servers (Vmware) for medium-small enterprises.
- Direct customer e-mail clients, LAN networks and Personal Computers' configuration Windows/MacOs/Linux.
- Co-workers support on Web/Domain names administration.
- Remote and phone help desk.

Business or sector Information and communication





2002 ICT technician

Internship with Provincia di Imperia (Local government administration), Imperia (Italy)

- Software and Hardware maintenance of employee's computers.
- New computers or components installation and configuration.
- Fixing network and printers issue.
- Scheduling of regular **back-ups** on magnetic tapes data storage.
- Data entry.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

2003–2006 Computer Science - No degree

Universita' degli studi di Genova, Genova (Italy)

https://informatica.dibris.unige.it/

1998–2002 Accountant / Programmer High-School Diploma

LINDEDSTANDING

I.I.S G. Ruffini, Imperia (Italy) http://www.ruffini.org/

PERSONAL SKILLS

Mother tongue(s) Italian

Foreign language(s)

UNDERSTANDING		SELANING		VVICITING		
Listening	Reading	Spoken interaction	Spoken production			
C1	C2	B2	C2	B2		
Understanding and	Understanding and expression of the language improved during the five-year stay in the United States					
A2	A2	A2	A2	A2		

SDEVKING

English

Portuguese

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user - B1 and B2: Independent user - C1 and C2: Proficient user Common European Framework of Reference for Languages

Communication skills

- Good **communication** skills with people from different work and cultural backgrounds.
- Good ability to create formal and informal interpersonal bonds, gained through work experience both in Italy and abroad.

Organisational / managerial skills

- Good ability to work and collaborate in groups to achieve a common goal by accepting and proposing constructive criticisms regarding the problems faced.
- Good organization of activities and personal commitments.

WOITING



Ability to structure the subdivision of tasks and objectives, both personal and of work groups.

Job-related skills

With 12+ years of experience in the IT/ telecommunications industry, I have acquired a tremendous amount of technical knowledge, mostly focused on **VoIP** and **Server technologies**.

I can manage mixed *Unix / Windows / macOS systems both in desktop or server\virtual server environments, implement targeted solutions, solve software/hardware problems and help the technical support team in all daily challenges.

I am expanding my competences in the **DevOps** field, especially **Docker** containers**Cloud** technologies (Azure, AWS) and stretching my knowledge about **software development**, focusing on Web Development, Python and C#.

My personal skills include a mentality focused on **problem solving** and attention to details as well as the ability to quickly acquire new concepts and the constant desire to **learn**.

Digital skills

	SELF-ASSESSMENT					
Information processing	Communication	Content creation	Safety	Problem- solving		
Proficient user	Proficient user	Proficient user	Proficient user	Proficient user		

Digital skills - Self-assessment grid

- Excellent knowledge of the VOIP protocol, SIP / H.323 signalling protocols and RTP media protocol.
- Excellent knowledge of personal computers: hardware, software, GNU/Linux (mostly Red Hat and Debian based), MS Windows7/10 and macOS operating systems.
- Very good knowledge of team collaboration tools like Slack and Trello and remote support software like TeamViewer.
- Good knowledge of G Suite.
- Router and network equipment configuration, TCP/IP protocol, DNS, DHCP and QOS, SMB and basic firewall configuration.
- Virtual Machine configuration in particular Oracle Virtual Box, VMware and Hyper-V.
- Basic knowledge of **Docker** containers and **Azure/AWS Cloud** platforms.
- Excellent knowledge of computer science fundamentals.
- Good knowledge of HTML5 + CSS3 + JS



Curriculum vitae Luca Arrigo

- I am a self-taught programmer, I am currently reviewing and deepening my abilities in particular with Python and C# languages and OOP/Functional programming paradigms.
- Good knowledge of GIT for version control.
- Excellent experience with text editors/IDEs such as Sublime Text 3, VsCode and Visual Studio
- Good knowledge of the MySQL DBMS.

Driving licence

В

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Certifications

 Certificate issued by MIT/edX for completion of the course "Introduction to Computer Science and Programming Using Python"

https://courses.edx.org/certificates/user/6418993/course/course-v1:MITx+6.00.1x_7+3T2015

 Certificate awarded by the University of Colorado/Coursera for completion of the "Beginning Game Programming with C#" course

https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/certificate/KVDEJAPVMM6W

Projects

 In 2018 I worked as a volunteer QA tester for the creation of the videogame Unavowed by Wadjet Eye Games. My role was to test the video game, report bugs and suggest their resolution directly to the developers team through the Trello collaboration platform. My name is present in the game credits

http://www.wadjeteyegames.com/games/unavowed/

Courses

Completed course "Learning How to Learn: Powerful mental tools to help you master tough subjects"

https://www.coursera.org/learn/learning-how-to-learn

I currently follow several **MOOCs** (Massive open online courses) on computer science topics http://mooc.org/

Completing the **Free Code Camp** course Web Developer Certificate https://www.freecodecamp.org/

Conferences

May 2017 - Chicago, **USA - ITW** - International Telecom Week conference, the largest meeting for the global wholesale telecommunication's industry.

Memberships

Between **2002** and **2007** I was a founder member of the **GUGLI** association, a Linux user group in Imperia, Italy, actively participating in the development of various events including Linux Day, Linux installation party and projects aimed at spreading **free software** especially in schools and public institutions in general.



Hobbies & Interests

- Video games. I am a long time gamer, playing with many genres, but I have a preference for Adventure Games and RPGs. It is largely due to video games if I pursued my IT career.
- Game Design/Dev. In my spare time I dedicate myself as a hobby to the study of design and development of video games in theory and practice; I am gaining experience in the use of AGS (Adventure Game Studio) and Unity. I also participated in several meetings of the indie game development scene in Boston
- I love to travel and immerse myself in the local culture of the countries I visit.
- I like reading books ranging from the Fantasy/Sci-fi genre to books on history or the physics of the
 universe, but also texts dealing with recent social problems such as global warming, the effect that
 automation will have on work, basic income and much more.
- I love watching movies and TV series from streaming services, but I'm not a fan of traditional TV.
- Basketball, NBA above all, is the only sport I am passionate about, I also like to practice it with my
 friends when I can.